

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







PMP and CSM certified Scrum Master with 5+ years of exp seeking roles in IT Project Management, Scrum Master, Quality Management, Risk Identification, Requirement Gathering, Client Servicing, Kanban, Agile, JIRA.

Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Current Designation: Scrum Master

Current Company: R System International

Current Location: Ghaziabad

Pref. Location: Chandigarh, Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon
Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Project Mgr-IT/Software

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services
Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Scrum Master, Project Manager-Software Engineering, Software Testing, Application Support, IT Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Risk Identification, Requirement Gathering, Client Servicing, Kanban, Agile, JIRA

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021

r 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Mssion-focused Scrum Master with extensive experience coaching and mentoring highly capable teams. Bilingual professional with more than 10+ years of experience delegating tasks and managing projects. Proficient in leading & motivating individuals to maximise levels of productivity. Managing the customer centric operations and consulting with customers about software system design and maintenance and ensuring the customer satisfaction by achieving delivery & service quality norms.

Experienced in Preparing Business Requirement Documents (BRD), Requirement Gathering and Executing Functional, Integration, System. An effective communicator with exceptional analytical skills with the ability to relate to people at any level of business and management.

Experienced in Preparing Business Requirement Documents (BRD), Requirement Gathering and Executing Functional, Integration, System, Unit, Regression and Black Box Testing.

Work Experience

- R System International as Scrum Master Sep 2018 to Till Date
 - * Planned agile best practices and encouraged team cohesion, overcoming impediments and hurdles to productivity.
 - * Evangelized Agile as strategic asset of culture and business value, inspiring teams in implementation of new tools and techniques.
 - * Facilitated Scrum framework sprint planning, backlog grooming, daily scrums, sprint reviews and sprint retrospective.
 - and sprint retrospective.

 * Led sprint reviews, daily scrums and planning meetings to realize full team engagement.
 - * Drove Scrum team progress to overcome obstacles and realize success throughout life of each sprint.
 - * Shielded scrum team from external interference for optimal productivity and success of agile
- process.
 * Managed product backlog and supported
 SCRUMframework for monthly sprint releases.
- * Collaborated with product owners, team members, technologists and other scrum masters to define solutions and drive progress.
- * Managed and motivated project teams to promote collaboration and keep members ontask and productive.

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

R1 RCM as Engineer Mar 2016 to Sep 2018

* Coaching teams to improve team collaboration and self-organization, guiding the teams to

increase their transparency and effectively track their progress by leveraging burn- downs and other information radiators like velocity charts, team impediments, Quality and requirement volatile, and facilitating effective and meaningful retrospective

- * Actively identifying the Scrum team, organizational impediments and collaborating with Coaches, product Managers & Directors for their removal for successful transformation.
- * Expertise in working with stakeholders, clients, teams across diverse cultures, backgrounds and different geographies.
- * Identified potential project risks and helped developed a mitigation plan to resolve potential issues.
- * Assessed each scrum team member's responsibilities and delegated tasks to balance each employee's workload.
- * Built and utilized reporting systems to keep customers and management in loop with latest information.
- * Gathered requirements, defined scopes, allocated resources and established schedules meeting or exceeding project demands.
- * Adjusted project plans to account for dynamic targets, staffing changes and operational specifications.
- R System International as Senior Software Engineer Jan 2015 to Sep 2015
 - * Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust [Type] solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
 - * Led cross-functional teams to analyze and understand enterprise-wide operational impacts and opportunities of technology changes.
 - Interfaced with cross-functional team of business

analysts, developers and technical support professionals to determine comprehensive list of requirement specifications for new applications.

- * Established online configuration knowledge base to support functionality by developing robust system application overview.
- Analyzed key aspects of business to evaluate factors driving results and summarized into presentations.
- * Consulted regularly with internal customers on application development project status, new project proposals and software-related technical issues.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Ch Charan Singh University (CCSU), Meerut in 2009

PG: MCA (Computers) from arunachal university of studies in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Certified Scrum Master

PMP

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	n Last Used Experience		
JIRA	2019	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
Planning Poker, MS Office	2019	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		
MS Visio	2019	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Hindi	Expert	✓	✓	✓
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Punjabi	Expert			✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.